How do you consume your music?
你是通过什么方式欣赏音乐的？
What format do you listen to it on?
你习惯用哪种格式听歌？
Technology now allows us to stream and download our favourite songs through websites and apps. This means it’s easy to access and it’s very portable, so we could enjoy it whenever and wherever we like.
如今的科技让我们可以通过各类网站和应用程序流媒体播放或下载喜爱的歌曲，这意味着音乐不仅易于获取，还极具便携性，让我们随时随地都能享受音乐。
So, it’s surprising to know that the popularity of some old tech is increasing.
但令人意外的是，一些老式音乐播放载体的受欢迎程度正在回升。
A number of musicians have been releasing their albums on vinyl and cassette tape.
许多音乐人开始重新以黑胶唱片和盒式磁带的形式发行专辑。
While this latter analogue technology lacks the good digital audio quality that we expect to hear today, in its heyday, it was a popular way for teenagers to enjoy recorded music.
尽管盒式磁带这种模拟技术，远不及如今我们熟悉的数字音频音质清晰，但在它的鼎盛时期，曾是青少年们欣赏录制音乐的主流方式。
The introduction of the Walkman portable cassette player in 1979, made by Sony, meant people could listen to music on the move for the first time.
1979年，索尼公司推出了随身听便携式磁带播放器，意味着第一次人们可以随时随地聆听音乐。
By the end of 1989, 83 million tapes were bought by British music fans, but the invention of the compact disc in the 1990s changed that.
到1989年底，英国乐迷共购买了8300万盒磁带，但20世纪90年代激光唱片（CD）的问世，彻底改变了这一局面。
Despite the demise of the cassette tape in the 90s, in the first six months of 2020, nearly 65,000 music cassettes were sold in the UK, according to the Official Charts Company – double the sales from the same period the previous year.
据英国官方排行榜公司的数据显示，尽管盒式磁带在20世纪90年代逐渐衰落，但在2020年上半年，英国的音乐磁带销量达到了近6.5万盒，是前一年同期销量的两倍。
Although this is only a small fraction of overall music sales, cassette tapes are physical items that can be kept and collected – not stored in the cloud.
虽然这一数字在音乐总销量中只占很小的比例，但磁带是实实在在的实体物品，可以被保存和收藏，而非存储在云端。
And the resurgence of the cassette has been helped by big names such as Billie Eilish, Ariana Grande and Justin Bieber, who have released their music on this format.
此外，比莉·艾利什、爱莉安娜·格兰德、贾斯汀·比伯等知名艺人也纷纷推出磁带版专辑，进一步推动了磁带的复兴潮流。
To listen to music on a cassette, you need a tape player or a personal stereo to play them on, but this hasn’t deterred the new younger audience – its recent popularity seems to be more about buying memorabilia.
想要播放磁带，你需要一台磁带播放器或便携式立体声音响，但这并没有打消年轻一代消费者的购买热情——磁带如今的流行，更多是因为它的收藏价值。
Gennaro Castaldo from the British Phonographic Industry told the BBC: “Younger consumers are now buying into their collectible appeal – as they have done with vinyl – and the more they do this, the greater the demand for labels and artists to cater to.”
英国唱片业协会的詹纳罗·卡斯塔尔多在接受BBC采访时表示：“就像追捧黑胶唱片一样，年轻消费者如今正为磁带的收藏魅力买单。他们的购买热情越高，唱片公司和艺人就越愿意迎合这种需求。”
But although cassettes won’t replace streaming as a way of listening to music, it does go to show how some tech never dies!
尽管磁带不会取代流媒体成为主流的音乐播放方式，但这也恰恰印证了一个道理：有些老物件永远不会彻底退出历史舞台。